<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Justin MK Lam | Blog</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/</link><description>Recent content on Justin MK Lam | Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 08:36:18 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://justinmklam.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Precision Sourdough: A Smart Lid for Your Starter</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2021/02/levain-monitor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 08:36:18 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2021/02/levain-monitor/</guid><description>A few years ago, I had the idea to track my sourdough starter using computer vision. It was neat to monitor it this way, but it was fairly impractical to do for each feeding since it required setting up a camera, downloading the images, and doing some manual image cropping before running it through my analysis script. The analysis was also only done after the fact, and what I really wanted was something that could tell me when the starter was ready to be used (or fed), or, if I missed the window of opportunity, how long ago it peaked.</description></item><item><title>3D Printed Engagement Ring</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2019/diy-wedding-ring/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 11:50:22 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2019/diy-wedding-ring/</guid><description>Professional photos from Justine Russo Photography. For readers of my blog, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice that I haven&amp;rsquo;t had any new content in the past year. For good reason though, as I got married in June! Aside from planning the proposal and wedding, I also had the lofty goal of designing and making my wife&amp;rsquo;s engagement ring.
With this post, I&amp;rsquo;d like to share my quest in designing and 3D printing the ring, along with some *minor* mistakes I made.</description></item><item><title>Archives</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/archives/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 16:56:13 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/archives/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Nordic nRF52 Development with Visual Studio Code</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2019/04/vscode-nrf52/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 14:14:25 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2019/04/vscode-nrf52/</guid><description>A few years ago, I created a tutorial on setting up Visual Studio Code for development with the STM32. Since I&amp;rsquo;ve also been developing on the Nordic nRF52, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share another tutorial to show how a project can be set up, flashed, and debugged using Visual Studio Code.
The template project discussed in this post can be found on Github.
Instructions The Nordic toolchain is cross-platform, but the instructions below are specifically for Linux.</description></item><item><title>Monitoring the Fermentation of Sourdough Starter with Computer Vision</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2018/06/sourdough-starter-monitor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 17:50:22 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2018/06/sourdough-starter-monitor/</guid><description>Bread, the quintessence of life. People have survived for centuries off this staple consisting only of flour, water, salt, and yeast. Try consuming all these ingredients separately, and you&amp;rsquo;ll be in for a digestive surprise. However, mix them together and let time do its thing, and the result is the release of profound flavour, texture, and nutrients that were previously locked away.
Despite it being relatively easy to turn dough into something that looks and feels like bread, the challenge is in squeezing every possible ounce of flavour and texture (using only those four ingredients) to achieve the embodiment of a true loaf of bread.</description></item><item><title>From Prototype to Cloud: A Python Recipe Converter</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2018/04/python-flask-heroku-tutorial/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 20:33:46 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2018/04/python-flask-heroku-tutorial/</guid><description>In case the title wasn&amp;rsquo;t clear, this blog post is about developing a web application using the Python programming language using Jupyter Lab, Flask, and the Heroku platform. If you were looking for an article on python recipes, you can start off with this one on making a poached Burmese python curry.
The Backstory The problem with online baking recipes is that the majority of them use volumetric units. As any civilized baker would know, Patricia&amp;rsquo;s 1 cup of flour may very well be different than Patrick&amp;rsquo;s 1 cup of flour.</description></item><item><title>Synchronous vs Asynchronous Ping Sweep in C# Windows Form</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2018/02/ping-sweeper/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 17:02:25 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2018/02/ping-sweeper/</guid><description>As a mechatronics engineer (in training), sometimes I like to pretend that I also know how to program.
In my most recent adventures to software land at MistyWest, I needed to write an application in C# that involved doing a ping sweep to find devices that were physically connected through ethernet. Since Google and Stack Overflow are my two best friends, I was able to find (what seemed to be) an off-the-net solution quite quickly.</description></item><item><title>Measuring the Spectral Characteristics of a Light Therapy Lamp</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2018/01/sad-lamp/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 09:42:57 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2018/01/sad-lamp/</guid><description>Disclaimer: Light therapy is one method of easing seasonal affective disorder (SAD); some people swear by it whereas others remain unaffected. This blog post does not intend to refute the effectiveness of light therapy, but rather to dig deeper into the technology behind these light therapy lamps to better educate fellow consumers.
Ah, the winter blues of Vancouver, BC. While some days bring bluebird skies and fresh pow for skiing, other days are downright gloomy.</description></item><item><title>Debugger Setup with GDB + OpenOCD in Visual Studio Code</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2017/10/vscode-debugger-setup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 14:24:52 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2017/10/vscode-debugger-setup/</guid><description>Visual Studio Code&amp;rsquo;s combination of functionality, customizability, and aesthetics makes it one of my favourite code editors. As such, I was set on making it work with embedded development since I was getting started with the STM32 line of microcontrollers. I was following the steps outlined in Mastering STM32 by Carmine Noviello (which is an excellent resource) until it said to use Eclipse, because life&amp;rsquo;s too short to use software with unnecessary bloat.</description></item><item><title>Annealing 3D Printed Plastics: Sous Vide Style</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2017/06/sous-vide-pla/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 15:56:53 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2017/06/sous-vide-pla/</guid><description>Featured on Hackaday and Fictiv Blog! Yep, you heard it right. With all the craze surrounding cooking sous vide these days, it was only a matter of time before someone decided to venture using it outside of the culinary world. Turns out that someone also had a 3D printer, and you won&amp;rsquo;t believe what happened next!
Click-bait headlines aside, this post is quite lengthy and not everyone may have the patience to get through it all.</description></item><item><title>Battery Power Protection and Regulation PCB</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2017/05/mistywest-mvs-pcb/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 11:30:56 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2017/05/mistywest-mvs-pcb/</guid><description>Objective:
Design a custom PCB to protect and regulate a 14.8V LiPo battery for use with an autonomous RC car Features:
12V undervoltage and 10A overcurrent protection 8.4V, 7.4V, and 5V regulated outputs Main Components:
LT6109 High Side Current Sense Amplifier RT8288AZSP Synchronous Step-Down Converter Skills:
Reading and understanding datasheets Schematic capture and PCB layout in Altium Designer Board bring-up Hardware debugging Achievement Unlocked:</description></item><item><title>blog</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/blog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 16:56:13 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/blog/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Overhead Robotic Gantry for Tethered VR Headsets</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2017/04/vr-gantry/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 09:26:50 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2017/04/vr-gantry/</guid><description>Project Overview Objective: Create an autonomous gantry to follow the HTC Vive headset around, keeping its cable behind the user at all times.
Motivation: An extravagant party prop for an evening at CES 2017, hosted by MistyWest.
Features:
CoreXY planar gantry design System built with 8020 aluminum extrusions and laser cut acrylic components Stepper motor control through Teensy 3.2 HTC Vive pose tracking through C++ Patent pending Skills:</description></item><item><title>Hakko-Style Solder Fume Extractor</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2017/03/solder-fume-extractor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 21:14:29 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2017/03/solder-fume-extractor/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been slowly getting into the land of electrical pixies. So now, not only will I be inhaling sawdust, I can also fill them with leaded solder (because we all know that the performance of leaded solder takes higher priority than the safety of lead-free solder)! However, because I still value living, I figured I should get something to help get the solder fumes away from my lungs.
At my current job with MistyWest, we have a nice, bench top solder fume extractor by Hakko.</description></item><item><title>Resources for 3D Printing with the MP Select Mini</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2017/03/3d-printing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 19:38:27 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2017/03/3d-printing/</guid><description>What&amp;rsquo;s better than an inexpensive 3D printer? Free sources of information! The items below are a resource list for 3D printing with the Monoprice Select Mini, all thanks to a lively community of users around the interwebz.
General Info Product Page: Monoprice Select Mini V1 Official User Manual: MP Select Mini User Manual Reddit: /r/MPSelectMiniOwners Facebook Group: MP Mini User Group Unofficial Wiki: MP Select Mini Wiki Community Knowledge Base: Google Doc Materials and Accessories Tested PLA Brands: Hatchbox AMZ3D Alternative Bed Surface: PEI Sheet, see RepRap Wiki for details Initial Set Up CAD Modeling Software (free for hobbyists and enthusiasts): Autodesk Fusion 360 Slicing Software: Ultimaker Cura Onboard WiFi for wireless printing: Connecting to WiFi through G-code Using Raspberry Pi and Octoprint for wireless printing: OctoPi Machine Settings General The machine settings below are based off the ones in the official user manual.</description></item><item><title>New Toy Tuesday: Monoprice Select Mini 3D Printer</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2017/03/mp-select-mini/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 15:56:53 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2017/03/mp-select-mini/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been bit by the 3D printing bug.
Like any tech-enthusiast, I have toyed with the idea of owning a 3D printer for quite some time. For my final year mechatronics design project, my partner and I designed an extravagent contraption to measure the yolk done-ness of a soft-boiled egg, which we called The PerfEGGct. We borrowed my roommate&amp;rsquo;s 3D printer to create the enclosure, and it turned out to be an indispensable tool during our prototyping process.</description></item><item><title>ESP8266 Sous Vide Controller</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2017/05/sous-vide-controller/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 12:28:27 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2017/05/sous-vide-controller/</guid><description>Project Summary Objective: Create a small, modular controller to regulate the temperature of a water bath.
Motivation: To get in on this cooking fad without dropping fat stacks of cash on an immersion circulator.
Features:
Crisp 0.96&amp;quot; OLED display Pushbutton rotary encoder provides simple user interaction Removable temperature plug through standard 3-pos audio connector Temperature controlled outlet to be used with any heating element (ie. rice cooker, slow cooker, etc.</description></item><item><title>Tired of Cables in VR? We Are Too.</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2016/tired-of-cables/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2016 23:02:43 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2016/tired-of-cables/</guid><description>Originally posted on Medium under MistyWest.
Virtual reality pushes the envelope of bleeding edge technology, allowing us to explore and experience worlds beyond our mortal imaginations. It gives us immersion in another dimension, providing an unprecedented medium for communication and story telling. If a picture is worth a thousand words, then virtual reality must be worth millions. Except there’s one thing keeping it grounded to reality: cables.
Since the first virtual reality headset that was hacked together in 2011, immersive head-mounted displays have progressed far and quickly.</description></item><item><title>Wooden Phone Stand</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2016/phone-stand/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 21:35:28 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2016/phone-stand/</guid><description>Phone stands are something that seem a little unnecessary, but once you have one then you&amp;rsquo;ll wonder how your desk lived without one. I&amp;rsquo;m a firm believer in having a dedicated place for everything as a solution to keep things tidy, so making a phone stand for my desk at work just made sense.
I started off on Google to look for existing designs I could imitate, but most fell short of not fitting my aesthetic needs.</description></item><item><title>Making Do With a Bargain Bin Bandsaw</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2016/bandsaw/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 20:58:10 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2016/bandsaw/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s generally known that cheap tools are usually not worth the trouble, but the deal on this bandsaw was simply too hard to pass up. With only a missing table, it was merely a quick woodworking project away from restoring its full functionality.</description></item><item><title>Engineer's Diary</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2016/10/engineers-diary/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 11:34:47 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2016/10/engineers-diary/</guid><description>Background: Between paper notebooks, post-it notes, OneNote, Evernote, and so many more, there is no shortage of ways to write things down. Each has its strengths and weaknesses, but none satisfied my requirements to act as a daily work log to record key events, thoughts, and milestones during my work day.
My paper notebook is excellent for free-form thoughts, sketches, and calculations, but I would want to keep a separate notebook to keep track of these sequential events.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 13:48:02 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/contact/</guid><description>Located in Vancouver, British Columbia. Drop me a line and I&amp;rsquo;ll get back to you within the day.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/about/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 12:58:43 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/about/</guid><description>I grew up watching Star Wars, and like any other eight-year old boy, I wanted to become a Jedi Knight. Maneuvering starfighters through the Hoth asteroid field whilst in aerial combat, jousting battle droids wielding nothing but a lightsaber, and having my hand sliced off to make space for my own mechno-arm were the epitomes of my childhood fantasy.
Reality came quite bluntly, yet these dreams continued to flourish. These days, they follow more along the lines of maneuvering through complex codebases, attacking architectural design challenges with a pen and paper, and putting my mechatronics background to good use by working on fun side projects.</description></item><item><title>MECH 458: Capstone 3D Optical Well Imager</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2016/06/mech-458-capstone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 12:57:32 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2016/06/mech-458-capstone/</guid><description>Introduction Objective: Develop an optical scanning system to be used for generating 3D models of well liners and casings with sub-millimeter accuracy.
How: As a team of five mechatronic and mechanical engineering students, we designed and constructed an alpha prototype of the optical 3D well imager.
Project Details Requirements and Specifications Optical Device must have a tolerance on distance measurement of 1 mm Device must have a camera circumferential resolution of 1.</description></item><item><title>New Workshop + Plywood Bench Stool</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2016/new-workshop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 15:39:56 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2016/new-workshop/</guid><description>My family moved into a new house, meaning that we finally have an actual garage instead of a measly carport. But what this really means is that I get a chance to claim space to set up an actual workshop! First project was naturally a workbench, which I put together using 2x4&amp;rsquo;s and a 3/4&amp;quot; MDF board for the work surface (see above). Second project was a bench stool, as shown in the following images below.</description></item><item><title>Adjustable Portable Power Supply</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2016/05/power-supply/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 17:29:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2016/05/power-supply/</guid><description>Objective: Build a cheap, portable, variable DC power supply.
Motivation: It was finally time to get my hands on a variable power supply for my electronics projects. Previous projects mainly involved Arduino, which was able to supply 5V and 3.3V with ease. However, the need for a supply with higher voltage, current, and flexibility eventually arose, resulting in the birth of this ghetto (but functional) power supply.
Limitations:
Only DC voltages available Max current is a function of input power and desired voltage (I=P/V) Current limiting feature is non-existent, so must be careful to not let the genie out of circuits Internals of the power supply.</description></item><item><title>MECH 423: Mechatronics Product Design</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2016/04/perfeggct/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 22:38:31 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2016/04/perfeggct/</guid><description>Background: When a hard boiled egg is spun on a table, it rotates freely since the inside is completely solid. With a raw egg, the liquid yolk sloshes around and resists rotation. By using math and physics, we can analyze the rotational oscillation of an egg and determine the yolk consistency.
&amp;ldquo;If it&amp;rsquo;s worth doing, it&amp;rsquo;s worth overdoing.&amp;rdquo; - Jaime Hyneman
Objective: Design and build a device to determine how cooked a boiled egg is using non-invasive techniques.</description></item><item><title>Boo-Boo with the Bamboo Bike</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2015/bamboo-bike-boo-boo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 20:50:37 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2015/bamboo-bike-boo-boo/</guid><description>As you probably already know, I made a bamboo bike which I&amp;rsquo;m very proud of. However, what you probably don&amp;rsquo;t know is that I made some mistakes in the process. The photo above shows the result of one of these progress speedbumps, and yes, I did indeed cry the day I had to cut those tubes out.
I started this project in November 2013 but failed to finish due splitting bamboo.</description></item><item><title>The Making of Project Haikuza: Part 2</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2015/making-haikuza-ii/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 23:49:59 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2015/making-haikuza-ii/</guid><description>The format of this series is an outline of my thought process during the development of @thehaikuza.
Poetry is hard To write when algorithms Are extremely dumb. I dont want my haiku generator to be a vegetarian chef. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing wrong with always making word salad, but eventually it&amp;rsquo;ll have to learn to make fancier things. A poetic risotto would be nice from time to time.
Leaving @thehaikuza to make complete gibberish wasnt what I had intended.</description></item><item><title>The Making of Project Haikuza: Part 1</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2015/making-haikuza-i/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2015 23:49:52 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2015/making-haikuza-i/</guid><description>The format of this series is an outline of my thought process during the development of @thehaikuza.
Haikus are simple Even children can write them maybe programs too? Nothing is cooler than algorithmic poetry. Except for maybe Carl Sagan. I heard he was a pretty cool guy.
I was listening to the radio while driving home one Sunday evening, and an ad came up for a university that was submitting computer-generated poetry to a literature competition.</description></item><item><title>Project Haikuza</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2015/07/haikuza/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 11:42:26 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2015/07/haikuza/</guid><description>Objective: Develop an algorithm to generate haikus using song lyrics.
Motivation: Because computational linguistics are cool.
Project: twitter.com/thehaikuza
Features:
Scrapes Virgin Radio&amp;rsquo;s broadcast history to find recently played songs Creates a song-based haiku queue in Google Sheets Generates a haiku using the queue as a reference and posts it on Twitter Checks for new tweets every 5 minutes and generates a relevant haiku, if requested Finds all song lyrics from Lyrics Wikia Runs on a Raspberry Pi Challenges:</description></item><item><title>Places To Be: Howe Sound Crest Trail</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2015/howe-sound-trail/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2015 23:14:15 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2015/howe-sound-trail/</guid><description>Originally posted on The Ubyssey.
Oh boy, some beginner trip this turned out to be.
As a new member of the VOC, it quickly became apparent to me how &amp;ldquo;beginner&amp;rdquo; can take on drastically different meanings. In retrospect, I should have read the wiki page on &amp;ldquo;The 5 Definitions of Beginner Friendly&amp;rdquo; before agreeing to this little excursion, but a bit of Type II fun (not fun during, but makes for a great story later) never killed anyone, right?</description></item><item><title>Co-op: Air Quality Calibration Chamber</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2015/mistywest-coop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 21:30:17 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2015/mistywest-coop/</guid><description>Background: Welcome to TZOA (pronounced &amp;lsquo;zoa&amp;rsquo;) - the world&amp;rsquo;s most advanced environment tracker. TZOA uses internal sensors to measure your air quality, temperature, humidity, atmospheric pressure, ambient light, and UV (sun) exposure, all in one wearable device.
Objective: Design and build a purified test chamber with zero air particulate to calibrate the TZOA devices against the DusTrak DRX 8533. An aerosolized cloud of ultrafine (0.3 - 20 μm) test dust was used to create the particle events.</description></item><item><title>External Ballistics Simulation</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2015/02/external-ballistics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 11:38:35 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2015/02/external-ballistics/</guid><description>Background: including (but not limited to) drag, gravity, air density, altitude, rotation of the bullet, and rotation of the Earth.
One solution is to connect a computer to a manual targeting system (ie. a scope) and estimate the corrected target location by accounting for these external factors. The user may then line the manual targeting system up with the corrected target location, hoping to the high heavens that the target will be hit upon releasing the projectile.</description></item><item><title>MECH 328: TrailRider Design Project</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2014/11/mech-328-trailrider/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 12:37:55 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2014/11/mech-328-trailrider/</guid><description>Background: The TrailRider™ is a specialized device to provide accessibility to the wilderness for those with limited mobility. It is intended for a seated rider propelled and balanced by assistants.
Objective: Expand the range of both riders and assistants who can ride safely use the Black Diamond TrailRider™.
How: As a team of seven mechanical engineering undergrads, we explored a range of areas for improvement and developed a new design to incorporate these features.</description></item><item><title>Co-op: Drill Cover User Study</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2014/coop-drill-cover/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 12:39:34 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2014/coop-drill-cover/</guid><description>Drill availability is a major limitation in developing counties, where surgeons turn to using manual hand-crank drills to perform surgeries. A common hardware drill equipped with a waterproof, sterilizable fabric cover provides a cost-effective solution in the operating room.</description></item><item><title>Bowling With car2go</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2014/08/car2go/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 12:37:42 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2014/08/car2go/</guid><description>Objective: Design a roof-mounted bowling rig for a car2go marketing event.
Constraints: Use a non-permanent method to securely attach the apparatus to the roof.
Venue: 2014 Vancouver Fringe Festival
Bowling rig set up and ready to roll.
Car2go bowling in action.</description></item><item><title>Award Winning Bamboo Bike</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2014/08/bamboo-bike/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 22:12:57 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2014/08/bamboo-bike/</guid><description>Objective: Exceed the Vancourite-hipster threshold by building a fixed-gear bicycle using bamboo and carbon fibre.
Challenges:
Constructing a frame jig to allow freedom around joints for carbon-fibre layup Accounting for the non-uniformity of bamboo poles at the frame lugs Maintaining compatibility with standard bicycle components Ensuring the frame is treated for typical"Wet" Coast weather Awards:
First Prize - Hand Tools Only Instructables Contest First Prize - Teach It!</description></item><item><title>MATLAB Photo Editing Script</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2014/01/photo-editing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 11:45:14 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2014/01/photo-editing/</guid><description>Objective: Develop a script to find and remove any differences in a series of photos.
Motivation: How to Remove People From Your Travel Using Photoshop
Framework: MATLAB
Script takes any number of images (preferably taken on a tripod) and combines them into one cleaned-up image.
Flowchart of the implemented algorithm.</description></item><item><title>Co-op: The Age Effect on Bicycle Helmets</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2013/coop-mea/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 12:37:10 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2013/coop-mea/</guid><description>Foam liners in bicycle helmets absorb energy during impacts. Manufacturers recommend replacing a helmet every 2 to 10 years to maintain optimal head protection. To investigate this recommendation, we quantified the material and impact attenuation properties of helmets to determine if they changed with age.</description></item><item><title>MECH 223: Hovercraft Competition</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2013/mech-223-hovercraft/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 12:22:15 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2013/mech-223-hovercraft/</guid><description>Teams were given 3 weeks to research, conceptualize, test, and refine their hovercrafts to compete in a class-wide battle of speed, cargo capacity, and maneuverability.</description></item><item><title>Men in Massage: Research Paper</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2011/12/men-in-massage-therapy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 17:51:38 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2011/12/men-in-massage-therapy/</guid><description>Originally written as a research paper for ENG 112 at UBC. Republished here for archival purposes.
Research Proposal According to Tom Delph-Janiurek, a “mis-performance of voice” may be necessary in order to gain authority in specific interactional spaces by creating a display of control and assertiveness (277). He proposes that the vocal performances in teaching spaces adapt to their social roles of authority by opposing the hegemonic heterosexuality in voices and perform vocal features of “drag” without giving up their gendered identities, contributing to and disrupting the “heterosexing of [teaching] space” (277).</description></item><item><title>LEGO Headphones</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2010/07/lego-headphones/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2010 12:37:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2010/07/lego-headphones/</guid><description>Background: I decided to combine the two things that I love most: music and LEGO. This whole project took me about a month and a half, very on and off. I&amp;rsquo;m quite pleased with how the headphones turned out in the end, as they are sturdy enough to be tossed around in a bag. My favourite part is that I can take it apart any time to make repairs that may be needed on the go.</description></item><item><title>A Minty-Fresh Power Pack</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2009/altoids/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2009 22:52:25 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2009/altoids/</guid><description>Before the ubiquity of powerbanks, there was nothing on the market to provide longer battery life for portable electronics. Connecting a female USB connector to four rechargable AA batteries opened up a new world of extended iPod playback.</description></item></channel></rss>