<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>woodworking on Justin MK Lam | Blog</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/tags/woodworking/</link><description>Recent content in woodworking on Justin MK Lam | Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 21:35:28 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://justinmklam.com/tags/woodworking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Wooden Phone Stand</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2016/phone-stand/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 21:35:28 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2016/phone-stand/</guid><description>Phone stands are something that seem a little unnecessary, but once you have one then you&amp;rsquo;ll wonder how your desk lived without one. I&amp;rsquo;m a firm believer in having a dedicated place for everything as a solution to keep things tidy, so making a phone stand for my desk at work just made sense.
I started off on Google to look for existing designs I could imitate, but most fell short of not fitting my aesthetic needs.</description></item><item><title>Making Do With a Bargain Bin Bandsaw</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2016/bandsaw/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 20:58:10 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2016/bandsaw/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s generally known that cheap tools are usually not worth the trouble, but the deal on this bandsaw was simply too hard to pass up. With only a missing table, it was merely a quick woodworking project away from restoring its full functionality.</description></item><item><title>New Workshop + Plywood Bench Stool</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2016/new-workshop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 15:39:56 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2016/new-workshop/</guid><description>My family moved into a new house, meaning that we finally have an actual garage instead of a measly carport. But what this really means is that I get a chance to claim space to set up an actual workshop! First project was naturally a workbench, which I put together using 2x4&amp;rsquo;s and a 3/4&amp;quot; MDF board for the work surface (see above). Second project was a bench stool, as shown in the following images below.</description></item><item><title>Boo-Boo with the Bamboo Bike</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2015/bamboo-bike-boo-boo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2015 20:50:37 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2015/bamboo-bike-boo-boo/</guid><description>As you probably already know, I made a bamboo bike which I&amp;rsquo;m very proud of. However, what you probably don&amp;rsquo;t know is that I made some mistakes in the process. The photo above shows the result of one of these progress speedbumps, and yes, I did indeed cry the day I had to cut those tubes out.
I started this project in November 2013 but failed to finish due splitting bamboo.</description></item><item><title>Award Winning Bamboo Bike</title><link>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2014/08/bamboo-bike/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 22:12:57 -0700</pubDate><guid>http://justinmklam.com/posts/2014/08/bamboo-bike/</guid><description>Objective: Exceed the Vancourite-hipster threshold by building a fixed-gear bicycle using bamboo and carbon fibre.
Challenges:
Constructing a frame jig to allow freedom around joints for carbon-fibre layup Accounting for the non-uniformity of bamboo poles at the frame lugs Maintaining compatibility with standard bicycle components Ensuring the frame is treated for typical"Wet" Coast weather Awards:
First Prize - Hand Tools Only Instructables Contest First Prize - Teach It!</description></item></channel></rss>