<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Justin MK Lam | Portfolio</title>
    <link>http://justinmklam.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Justin MK Lam | Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 22:18:22 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://justinmklam.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mechatronics</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/sections/mechatronics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 22:18:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/sections/mechatronics/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mechanical</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/sections/mechanical/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 17:34:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/sections/mechanical/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electrical</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/sections/electrical/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 17:34:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/sections/electrical/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/sections/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 22:21:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/sections/software/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/blog-archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 23:08:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/blog-archive/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/blog-index/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 23:08:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/blog-index/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Battery Power Protection and Regulation PCB</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/projects/elec/mistywest-mvs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 21:26:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/projects/elec/mistywest-mvs/</guid>
      <description>Background:
Objective:
Motivation:
Features:
 Foo 1 Foo 2   Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, the numbers don&amp;rsquo;t really matter  TEXT
TEXT</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>blog</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/pages/blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 16:56:13 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/pages/blog/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overhead Robotic Gantry for Tethered VR Headsets</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/projects/mecha/vr-gantry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 09:26:50 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/projects/mecha/vr-gantry/</guid>
      <description>Objective: Create an autonomous gantry to follow the HTC Vive headset around, keeping its cable behind the user at all times.
Motivation: An extravagant party prop for an evening at CES 2017, hosted by MistyWest.
Features:
 CoreXY planar gantry design System built with 8020 aluminum extrusions and laser cut acrylic components Stepper motor control through Teensy 3.2 HTC Vive pose tracking through C++ Patent pending  Skills:
 Mechanical design with rapid prototyping methods C++ software development Arduino-based firmware development  Sources:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESP8266 Sous Vide Controller</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/projects/elec/sous-vide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 12:28:27 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/projects/elec/sous-vide/</guid>
      <description>Objective: Create a small, modular controller to regulate the temperature of a water bath.
Motivation: To get in on this cooking fad without dropping fat stacks of cash on an immersion circulator.
Features:
 Crisp 0.96&amp;rdquo; OLED display Pushbutton rotary encoder provides simple user interaction Removable temperature plug through standard 3-pos audio connector Temperature controlled outlet to be used with any heating element (ie. rice cooker, slow cooker, etc.) Always on outlet for water circulator Temperature logging over wifi  Source: Github</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bargain Bandsaw Project</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/blog-posts/bandsaw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 20:58:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/blog-posts/bandsaw/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted a bandsaw. Being able to cut wood, plastics, etc. quickly and with flexibility has been a dream in my home shop. When I found an ad on Craigslist for a portable bandsaw for $50, I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist. The main caveat was that it was missing a table, but that wasn&amp;rsquo;t a big enough issue to turn me away from this killer deal.
Fresh off Craigslist in its table-naked glory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engineer&#39;s Diary</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/projects/software/engineers-diary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 12:39:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/projects/software/engineers-diary/</guid>
      <description>Background: Between paper notebooks, post-it notes, OneNote, Evernote, and so many more, there is no shortage of ways to write things down. Each has its strengths and weaknesses, but none satisfied my requirements to act as a daily work log to record key events, thoughts, and milestones during my work day.
My paper notebook is excellent for free-form thoughts, sketches, and calculations, but I would want to keep a separate notebook to keep track of these sequential events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>View All</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/view-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 23:08:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/view-all/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cv</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/pages/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 16:56:13 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/pages/cv/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/pages/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 13:48:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/pages/contact/</guid>
      <description>Located in Vancouver, British Columbia. Drop me a line and I&amp;rsquo;ll get back to you within the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/pages/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 12:58:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/pages/about/</guid>
      <description>I grew up watching Star Wars, and like any other eight-year old boy, I wanted to become a Jedi Knight. Maneuvering starfighters through the Hoth asteroid field whilst in aerial combat, jousting battle droids wielding nothing but a lightsaber, and having my hand sliced off to make space for my own mechno-arm were the epitomes of my childhood fantasy.
Reality came quite bluntly, yet these dreams continued to flourish. These days, they follow more along the lines of developing a steering system for a model hovercraft providing optimized maneuverability, attacking design challenges with a pen and paper, and studying the possibilities of bionic technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MECH 458: Capstone 3D Optical Well Imager</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/projects/mech/mech-458-capstone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 12:57:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/projects/mech/mech-458-capstone/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Objective: Develop an optical scanning system to be used for generating 3D models of well liners and casings with sub-millimeter accuracy.
How: As a team of five mechatronic and mechanical engineering students, we designed and constructed an alpha prototype of the optical 3D well imager.
Requirements and Specifications Optical
 Device must have a tolerance on distance measurement of 1 mm Device must have a camera circumferential resolution of 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adjustable Portable Power Supply</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/projects/elec/power-supply/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 17:29:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/projects/elec/power-supply/</guid>
      <description>Objective: Build a cheap, portable, variable DC power supply.
Motivation: It was finally time to get my hands on a variable power supply for my electronics projects. Previous projects mainly involved Arduino, which was able to supply 5V and 3.3V with ease. However, the need for a supply with higher voltage, current, and flexibility eventually arose, resulting in the birth of this ghetto (but functional) power supply.
Limitations:
 Only DC voltages available Max current is a function of input power and desired voltage (I=P/V) Current limiting feature is non-existent, so must be careful to not let the genie out of circuits</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MECH 423: Mechatronics Product Design</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/projects/mecha/perfeggct/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 22:38:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/projects/mecha/perfeggct/</guid>
      <description>Background: When a hard boiled egg is spun on a table, it rotates freely since the inside is completely solid. With a raw egg, the liquid yolk sloshes around and resists rotation. By using math and physics, we can analyze the rotational oscillation of an egg and determine the yolk consistency.
 &amp;ldquo;If it&amp;rsquo;s worth doing, it&amp;rsquo;s worth overdoing.&amp;rdquo; - Jaime Hyneman
 Objective: Design and build a device to determine how cooked a boiled egg is using non-invasive techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Haikuza</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/projects/software/haikuza/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 12:36:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/projects/software/haikuza/</guid>
      <description>Objective: Develop an algorithm to generate haikus using song lyrics.
Motivation: Because computational linguistics are cool.
Project: twitter.com/thehaikuza
Features:
 Scrapes Virgin Radio&amp;rsquo;s broadcast history to find recently played songs Creates a song-based haiku queue in Google Sheets Generates a haiku using the queue as a reference and posts it on Twitter Checks for new tweets every 5 minutes and generates a relevant haiku, if requested Finds all song lyrics from Lyrics Wikia Runs on a Raspberry Pi  Challenges:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>External Ballistics Simulation</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/projects/software/external-ballistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 12:36:19 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/projects/software/external-ballistics/</guid>
      <description>Background: including (but not limited to) drag, gravity, air density, altitude, rotation of the bullet, and rotation of the Earth.
One solution is to connect a computer to a manual targeting system (ie. a scope) and estimate the corrected target location by accounting for these external factors. The user may then line the manual targeting system up with the corrected target location, hoping to the high heavens that the target will be hit upon releasing the projectile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MECH 328: TrailRider Design Project</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/projects/mech/mech-328-trailrider/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 12:37:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/projects/mech/mech-328-trailrider/</guid>
      <description>Background: The TrailRider™ is a specialized device to provide accessibility to the wilderness for those with limited mobility. It is intended for a seated rider propelled and balanced by assistants.
Objective: Expand the range of both riders and assistants who can ride safely use the Black Diamond TrailRider™.
How: As a team of seven mechanical engineering undergrads, we explored a range of areas for improvement and developed a new design to incorporate these features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Co-op: Drill Cover User Study</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/blog-posts/coop-drill-cover/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 12:39:34 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/blog-posts/coop-drill-cover/</guid>
      <description>Background: Drill availability is a major limitation in developing countries, where surgeons turn to using manual hand-crank drills to perform surgeries. A common hardware drill equipped with a waterproof, sterilizable fabric cover provides a cost-effective solution in the operating room.
Objective: Develop, conduct, and analyze a study to quantify the drilling performance of the drill cover solution and compare it against a commercial surgical drill and a manual hand-crank drill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>car2go Bowling</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/projects/mech/car2go/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2014 12:37:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/projects/mech/car2go/</guid>
      <description>Objective: Design a roof-mounted bowling rig for a car2go marketing event.
Constraints: Use a non-permanent method to securely attach the apparatus to the roof.
Venue: 2014 Vancouver Fringe Festival
(function(d, s, id) {var js, fjs = d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0];if (d.getElementById(id)) return;js = d.createElement(s); js.id = id;js.src = &#34;//connect.facebook.net/en_US/sdk.js#xfbml=1&amp;version=v2.6&#34;;fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js, fjs);}(document, &#39;script&#39;, &#39;facebook-jssdk&#39;));</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Award Winning Bamboo Bike</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/projects/mech/bamboo-bike/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 22:12:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/projects/mech/bamboo-bike/</guid>
      <description>Objective: Exceed the Vancourite-hipster threshold by building a fixed-gear bicycle using bamboo and carbon fibre.
Challenges:
 Constructing a frame jig to allow freedom around joints for carbon-fibre layup Accounting for the non-uniformity of bamboo poles at the frame lugs Maintaining compatibility with standard bicycle components Ensuring the frame is treated for typical&#34;Wet&#34; Coast weather  Awards:
 First Prize - Hand Tools Only Instructables Contest First Prize - Teach It!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MECH 355: Tron Game</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/blog-posts/mech-355-tron/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 12:36:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/blog-posts/mech-355-tron/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photo Editing Script</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/projects/software/photo-editing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 12:25:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/projects/software/photo-editing/</guid>
      <description>Objective: Develop a script to find and remove any differences in a series of photos.
Motivation: How to Remove People From Your Travel Using Photoshop
Framework: MATLAB
Script takes any number of images (preferably taken on a tripod) and combines them into one cleaned-up image.
Flowchart of the implemented algorithm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Co-op: The Age Effect on Bicycle Helmets</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/blog-posts/coop-mea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 12:37:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/blog-posts/coop-mea/</guid>
      <description>Objective: Determine if age has an effect on the mechanical properties of bicycle helmets.
Tasks:
 Conducted 1630 helmet impact attenuation tests to measure the effect of age and use on bicycle helmet foam Developed scripts in MATLAB to autonomously post-process the impact data and organize information according to existing helmet databases Wrote the Methods section of the research report to be submitted to the Accident Prevention &amp;amp; Analysis Journal Assisted in protocol development of the helmet and foam core impact attenuation tests  Company: MEA Forensic Engineers &amp;amp; Scientists</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MECH 223: Hovercraft Competition</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/blog-posts/mech-223-hovercraft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 12:22:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/blog-posts/mech-223-hovercraft/</guid>
      <description>For our final MECH2 design project at UBC, we were given three weeks to research, conceptualize, test, and build a functional hovercraft. The end goal was a class-wide competition of speed, cargo capacity, maneuverability, and driving skill. Budget was limited since costs came out of our own pockets, so we set out to build an inexpensive hovercraft using parts from the hardware and dollar store.
Our result: 5th place out of 30 teams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LEGO Headphones</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/projects/mech/lego-headphones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2010 12:37:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/projects/mech/lego-headphones/</guid>
      <description>Background: I decided to combine the two things that I love most: music and LEGO. This whole project took me about a month and a half, very on and off. I&amp;rsquo;m quite pleased with how the headphones turned out in the end, as they are sturdy enough to be tossed around in a bag. My favourite part is that I can take it apart any time to make repairs that may be needed on the go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Altoids Portable Charger</title>
      <link>http://justinmklam.com/blog-posts/altoids/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2009 22:52:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justinmklam.com/blog-posts/altoids/</guid>
      <description>Before the ubiquity of powerbanks, there was nothing on the market to provide longer battery life for portable electronics. Connecting a female USB connector to four rechargable AA batteries opened up a new world of extended iPod playback. I built a simple, rechargable battery pack to keep the tunes playing on long road trips.
The iPod is alive!
President&amp;#39;s Choice rechargable batteries and some janky wiring is all it took.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>